<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sebastianrowan.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://sebastianrowan.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-01-30T16:56:40+00:00</updated><id>https://sebastianrowan.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sebastian Rowan</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Testimony in opposition to SB 439</title><link href="https://sebastianrowan.github.io/blog/2024/sb439-testimony/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testimony in opposition to SB 439"/><published>2024-01-25T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-25T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sebastianrowan.github.io/blog/2024/sb439-testimony</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sebastianrowan.github.io/blog/2024/sb439-testimony/"><![CDATA[<p>Senate Bill SB-439 was introduced in the New Hampshire State Senate in January 2024. The bill would prevent the state of New Hampshire from contracting or doing any business with any entity standing in solidarity with the people of Palestine by boycotting Israel. I joined about 20 others in attending the January 24, 2024 meeting of the Senate Executive Departments and Administration Committee to register our opposition to this bill. My testinomy to the committee is below:</p> <hr/> <p>Good morning, members of the committee.</p> <p>My name is Sebastian Rowan, I live in Manchester, and I am here this morning to register my opposition to SB 439 and urge the committee to vote this bill as inexpedient to legislate.</p> <p>The <strong>State</strong> of Israel is currently committing a genocide of Palestinians in Gaza. Since October 7, Israel has killed more than 25,000 people. Israel has murdered more than 10,000 children. 1.9 million people, over 80% of Gaza’s population, have been displaced from their home with little hope of ever being allowed to return. The atrocities we are seeing every day in Gaza are part of a decades long brutal military occupation of Palestinian territory by the Israeli Military. I support the BDS movement because to do otherwise is to support genocide.</p> <p>In the text of SB 439, Articles 1-3 of Section 1 explain that the primary purpose of New Hampshire’s support for Israel is founded on economic development. I oppose this bill because I do not believe my state’s economy should rely on or support any nation engaged in genocide, ethnic cleansing, or apartheid.</p> <p>Only after highlighting the economic importance of our state’s relationship with Israel, does the bill go on to attempt to equate boycotts of Israel with antisemitism. Let me be very clear. Antisemitism has no home in New Hampshire, and I believe that everyone should feel safe and welcome to proudly practice their religion here or anywhere else without fear of persecution or harassment.</p> <p>The actions of the State of Israel do not reflect the will of all Jewish people. To assume that every Jewish person supports Israel and its actions is, in fact, antisemitic. As Congressman Jerry Nadler said on the House floor last month, anyone who suggests that all anti-Zionism is antisemitism “is either intellectually disingenuous or just factually wrong”<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p> <p>The purpose of the BDS movement is to boycott Jewish-owned businesses. The purpose is specifically to oppose the State of Israel’s oppression of the Palestinian people; to boycott companies which provide material support for Israel’s illegal occupation of Palestinian territory. To boycott the companies that develop the technology used in Israel’s Habsora program which uses AI to generate bombing targets and that was described by a former Israeli intelligence officer as a “mass assassination factory”<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>. To boycott companies like NSO Group which developed the Pagasus spyware program<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> which has been used by authoritarian regimes around the world to track and harass journalists, including Jamal Khashoggi, who was assassinated and dismembered by the Saudi government <sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>. Or to boycott companies like Pizza Hut who provide free pizza to IDF soldiers and run ads in Israel mocking starving Palestinian prisoners <sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>.</p> <p>Boycotts have long been a legitimate form of political speech in this country going all the way back to the Boston Tea Party. I find it unbelievable that New Hampshire, a State whose motto is “Live Free or Die” and whose constitution enshrines the right of revolution for its people, would pass this bill which would fundamentally limit political speech and essentially require all New Hampshire business owners to swear allegiance to a foreign authoritarian government.</p> <p>Please do the right thing. Please be on the right side of history. Please vote against this bill.</p> <p>Thank you all for hearing my testimony this morning, and I’m happy to answer any questions from the members.</p> <div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"> <ol> <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote"> <p>https://nadler.house.gov/news/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=395107 <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote"> <p>https://www.972mag.com/mass-assassination-factory-israel-calculated-bombing-gaza/ <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote"> <p>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pegasus_(spyware) <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote"> <p>https://www.seattletimes.com/business/apnewsbreak-undercover-agents-target-cybersecurity-watchdog-2/ <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> <li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote"> <p>https://www.azcentral.com/story/entertainment/dining/2024/01/23/pizza-hut-boycott/72323899007/ <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> </ol> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="politics"/><category term="politics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testimony given in opposition to SB 439 during the January 24th, 2024 meeting of the New Hampshire Senate Executive Departments and Administration Committee]]></summary></entry></feed>